<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sics on Tiliaradix Blog</title>
    <link>https://tiliaradix.com/tags/sics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sics on Tiliaradix Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 15:50:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiliaradix.com/tags/sics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Piggie parts</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/piggie-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 15:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/piggie-parts/</guid>
      <description>It was fun in the taxi on the way to the venue where we were to talk, FUDAN Uni. I felt quite &#39;up&#39; by then, excited and positive. I felt like I kept noticing small details around me, as if I was very attentive, but lacked impulse suppressive skills. Like a kid on speed. Poor Alexa had to answer many insightful and nuanced questions about electric mopeds, trees dressed with ropes etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verrrry, verrrry important persons</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/verrrry-verrrry-important-persons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/verrrry-verrrry-important-persons/</guid>
      <description>I got a quite nice hotel room :), 19th floor, Fuxuan hotel.
Very mixed messages.
The second day, Nov 2nd, was the beginning of the event with a grand opening and unveiling of some plaquette or sth. We, Thiemo and I, didn&#39;t really understand everything. There were 400 Chinese and 3 Swedes. Prof Kalle from KTH were there as well and held a talk about IoT they were involved in. Everything else was in Chinese but we had headphones with real time translation by two translators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in an old track</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/back-in-an-old-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 15:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/back-in-an-old-track/</guid>
      <description>So, last time I was in China (for Ubicomp), I was supposed to hold a Contiki-tutorial in Shanghai afterwards but for different reasons it was postponed, or something. The Chinese organizers never decided on a date until it was too late. Nvm.
A week after returning home they had apparently decided and I was asked if I could go back go China and take care of it. Of course I&#39;ll do it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beijing Banquet</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/beijing-banquet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 11:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/beijing-banquet/</guid>
      <description>The second to last day of Ubicomp 2011 included a banquet. After the last session of presentations, we were taken in buses, comfortable coaches, to the lake by the Summer Palace. The driver was absolutely ruthless, driving fast, honking his horn and rarely steering away from bikers or pedestrians. Not even kids were safe from this beast of the road. Biggest goes first I guess. Well, no casualties at least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Ubicomp presentations</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/some-ubicomp-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 02:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/some-ubicomp-presentations/</guid>
      <description>Starting off strong with the SmileCounter system! By being encouraged to smile, this will eventually make you happier, even if the initial smiles are not natural. Funny! Japanese (of course ;))
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.bithappens.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/20110919-104423.jpg&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;http://www.bithappens.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/20110919-104423.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;20110919-104423.jpg&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;alignnone size-full&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
The main hall of main buildning.
CoDine, featuring a ketchup-printer for remote dining.
FlyingBuddy! You can send it to see ahead, or tell it to go buy things if you are in your car and out of food!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubicomp 11 workshop</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/ubicomp-11-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 15:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/ubicomp-11-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Keynote by Christopher Mustafa Kirwan
Some other presentations:
Our own presentation went very well! We knew the stuff, were lagom prepared and acted with confidence. Got great critique from Kirwan. Well done both of us! :)
And here is the Google sponsored reception. The banquet is on tuesday though.
And finally a few of us ended up on a reggae bar. Lots of pushy peeps on the way in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagged at Tianamen square</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/tagged-at-tianamen-square/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 01:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/tagged-at-tianamen-square/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we (Jordi and I) mostly worked on the presentation for today, but in the evening we took the subway downtown. We went to see the Forbidden city and the Himmelska fridens torg (a few call it Tianamen square though), or rather we just took the subway there and walked from there.
At the street there were many guys walking around selling their service of snapping a pic of you and printing it on a portable printer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being in Beijing</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/being-in-beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 04:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/being-in-beijing/</guid>
      <description>The flight with Qatar Airways went well. Got an ok seat, but what makes them slightly better is all the complimentary stuff, like free drinks (incl whiskey :) ), and the nice entertainment system. No dancing bears, but a screen in front of you with a lot of movies to choose from. 6h to Doha, cap of Qatar, 2h wait, then 7:40h to Beijing. Took a taxi to the hotel, Park Plaza Beijing Science park, only ca 100Y (~100kr).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out mobile posting</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/trying-out-mobile-posting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 21:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/trying-out-mobile-posting/</guid>
      <description>This is just a test post to see if posting via the Iphone Wordpress app works good. Apparently, to enable mobile posting, you have to enable XML-RPC in your wordpress settings.
This was me working in the sun :).
This is the starter course we had at the conference today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
