<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hobby on Tiliaradix Blog</title>
    <link>https://tiliaradix.com/tags/hobby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hobby on Tiliaradix Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiliaradix.com/tags/hobby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build: Barnfind (in progress)</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-barnfind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-barnfind/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Barnfind (in progress) 🔗Sneak peek 🔗Meta 🔗It&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for various barn finds to pop into existance. The term more or less signifies something rare, forgotten in time and found way later. Often a rural farmer or excentric collector. While tanks aren&amp;rsquo;t that usual, more common is it to find old cars.
This diorama is a play on that theme.
Here, a farmer had a German WW2 tank in his barn, forgotten in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Clicker</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-clicker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-clicker/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Clicker 🔗Sneak peek 🔗Clicker diorama.
Meta 🔗The Clicker is a creature (?) in the world of The Last of Us, made by Naughty Dog.
Clicker.
The Clickers are originally humans, that have fallen to a fungus infection. The fungus, of the Cordyceps genus, affects, takes over, control over the body. It is famously documented on insects in the Planet Earth documentary, however the human infection is a fictious extrapolation as a plot device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Nixie (in progress)</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-nixie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-nixie/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Nixie (in progress) 🔗Sneak peek 🔗Before hitting the reflow oven.
Some Nixie tubes, IN-12A.
Some more Nixie tubes.
Meta 🔗Previously&amp;hellip; 🔗I saw this project, DekuNuken/exixe, and felt that hey, this is really cool and what I could use! But, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d like them differently.
For starters, I&amp;rsquo;d like them to run over I2C instead of SPI, to make it easier with strings of nixies. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to use firmware I&amp;rsquo;ve already developed (eg my contiki port for msp430) and chips I already had (msp430), aaaand I thought I could do a cleaner job with the layout of the transistors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Ohmu</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-ohmu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-ohmu/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Ohmu 🔗This is the buildlog for my Ohmu diorama.
Sneak peek 🔗Hello, Ohmu.
Meta 🔗The Ohmu is a creature from the 1984 anime Nausicaä of the Valley of the Wind.
It was directed by Hayao Miyazaki, who co-founded Studio Ghibli.
Brief synopsis courtesy of Wikipedia:
 Taking place in a future post-apocalyptic world, the film tells the story of Nausicaä (Shimamoto), the young princess of the Valley of the Wind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
