<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cambodia on Tiliaradix Blog</title>
    <link>https://tiliaradix.com/tags/cambodia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cambodia on Tiliaradix Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 06:42:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiliaradix.com/tags/cambodia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diverse leftovers</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/diverse-leftovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 06:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/diverse-leftovers/</guid>
      <description>These are some leftovers I haven&#39;t written about before.
There were some eerie, creepy animals in the Cambodian forest that scared the s!!t out of us when we were exploring a temple that had closed for the day and was void of people. The sun had just set when these animals, called &amp;quot;rajj&amp;quot; started synchronizing their sound in time and frequency. Like being in a horror movie.
VID HERE, fix later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambodia in the clear</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/cambodia-in-the-clear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 11:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/cambodia-in-the-clear/</guid>
      <description>So, we have now left Cambodia behind us. We visited some more temples, but left many behind. There are simply too many! Bantey Srey is an area which is supposed to be good, but 37 km from Siem Reap so we didn&#39;t have time for it.
Siem Reap is a small town, ca 10.000 inhabitants, but it has a club I feel Stockholm is lacking. We joined some locals for some interesting dishes, and I quote, &amp;quot;Egg has baby&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day of temples</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/first-day-of-temples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 08:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/first-day-of-temples/</guid>
      <description>We took the Tuk tuk to Angkor Wat early in the morning. Good to get there so early but it was unfortunately cloudy.
More tuktuk
We didn&#39;t stay at AW, instead we left for Ta Prohm which is considered a sunset temple, ie looking better at the sunset. Thus, it&#39;s more empty during the morning.
Also visited Ta Keo.
Saw a cool centipede which fortunately enough was slow and didn&#39;t seem to have an appetite for human flesh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entered Siem Reap</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/entered-siem-reap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 16:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/entered-siem-reap/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I heard right, there def is corruption. After shooing away the expected touts, first thing that happens is that a welldecorated police officer sees my shopping bag of food and &amp;quot;asks&amp;quot; me to give something because he&#39;s hungry. In front of other cops and tourists, without shame. I find it a little funny and gives him a bun (fika ftw!). Next thing, they ask for 25$ instead of 20$. Wasn&#39;t a problem though, I just said clearly and with my thunderous authority that it&#39;s only 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambodian communication</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/cambodian-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 16:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/cambodian-communication/</guid>
      <description>Chatuchak market was as cramped and chaotic as I remembered, so many booths and people in narrow lanes. The roof made it a very warm and humid experience, although we didn&amp;rsquo;t buy anything there were plenty of maybes. Then we roamed the Siam malls and I bought nice goggles for a really nice price (900B is ca 180kr). Looking forward to using them!
We changed hotel from Davis Bkk hotel at Sukhumvit (awesome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermedio and arriving</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/intermedio-and-arriving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 15:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/intermedio-and-arriving/</guid>
      <description>We had almost five hours transfertime at Charles de Gaulles, Paris,before the flight to Bangkok so we took a quick detour to have some red wine at a small café close to Notre Dame. From CDG it was a 45 min at 8.5€ trainride. Never been to Paris before, and it was very nice! I will come back here some other time :).
We flew with Air France and I must say I&#39;m impressed!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
