<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vietnam on Tiliaradix log</title>
    <link>https://tiliaradix.com/tags/vietnam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vietnam on Tiliaradix log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 07:11:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiliaradix.com/tags/vietnam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hoi An hotel</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/hoi-an-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 07:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/hoi-an-hotel/</guid>
      <description>We took the Jetstar late evening-flight to Da Nang. It was the most cramped flight I&#39;ve ever had. I had just a few cm left for my legs, and the Vietnamese man sitting next to me was very friendly, a little too friendly so to speak. First I thought that he was just rude and taking up space but when I was almost falling asleep I felt his hand caressing my bare knee and I briskly woke up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cramped Cu Chi</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/cramped-cu-chi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 14:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/cramped-cu-chi/</guid>
      <description>Cu Chi is the area (district? Village?) where, among other things the Americans had a big army base during the war and the VC built an intricate system of tunnels, 200 km of them. The reason was to hide VC fighters, covert regrouping and surprise attacks.
As the US used B52 bombers with 200-450 kg bombs, carpet bombing large areas at a time, the VC built the tunnels in levels. First level was &amp;lt;=3m deep and would not survive those bombs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surreal in Saigon</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/surreal-in-saigon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 14:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/surreal-in-saigon/</guid>
      <description>The night before we left Saigon/HCMC we decided to head on out, making the city the most insecure since the &#39;70-ies. Turns out Saigon had a few surprises itself.
According to Google searches, the best clubs would be Gossip club, Apocalypse Now, Lush, and Velvet. We decided to start at the supposed THE place to go to: Gossip.
No entrance fee, nice! Thank you pale falang-skin and shining smile ;) The music was reeeeeally heavy, the volume was insane and there was a crowd dancing on a small dance floor podium in the center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saigon</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/saigon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 12:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/saigon/</guid>
      <description>We arrived in a intermittently very rainy Saigon. Or Ho Chi Minh City/HCMC as it is called now after the latest war but many still call it Saigon.
Traffic in the rain:
There should have been a video here but your browser does not seemto support it. We got a really nice hotel room but stayed only one night before we moved on to next one. Might have said it before but the hotels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firewalls</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 12:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/firewalls/</guid>
      <description>Oh, and Facebook is banned in the free-thinking peoples republic of Vietnam. I can of course get around via proxy but&amp;hellip; Well well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War stuff</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/war-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 12:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/war-stuff/</guid>
      <description>We went to see the War remnants museum, which is a museum for the Vietnam/American war. There were some fighter jets, tanks, old bombs and equipment and guns on display but most moving was the very many photos and stories from both V&#39;s and A&#39;s.
Saw a woman/girl that took photos of many of the nasty pics of mutilated bodies etc. Interesting. She seemed focused on those.
There were also devices from one of the worlds first wireless sensor network deployments on display, the ADSID.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
