<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>electronics on Tiliaradix Blog</title>
    <link>https://tiliaradix.com/tags/electronics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in electronics on Tiliaradix Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiliaradix.com/tags/electronics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How We Do It: Making Things Happen At Specific Times of the Day</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-we-do-it-making-things-happen-at-specific-times-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-we-do-it-making-things-happen-at-specific-times-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
Connected products need scheduled actions. Scheduled actions require time synchronized deceives. Here is we make that happen.
In our daily lives, we are governed by time and schedules. We may wake up at 6:30 AM, take the bus at 7:34 AM, start work at 8:10 AM, pick up from school at 4:00 PM - based on synchronized and often fixed times of day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Nixie (in progress)</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-nixie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-nixie/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Nixie (in progress) 🔗Sneak peek 🔗Before hitting the reflow oven.
Some Nixie tubes, IN-12A.
Some more Nixie tubes.
Meta 🔗Previously&amp;hellip; 🔗I saw this project, DekuNuken/exixe, and felt that hey, this is really cool and what I could use! But, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d like them differently.
For starters, I&amp;rsquo;d like them to run over I2C instead of SPI, to make it easier with strings of nixies. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to use firmware I&amp;rsquo;ve already developed (eg my contiki port for msp430) and chips I already had (msp430), aaaand I thought I could do a cleaner job with the layout of the transistors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: DigiDev</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-digidev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-digidev/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: DigiDev 🔗The Goal 🔗Design a board using inexpensive 2-layer design.
The Challenge 🔗2-layer designs present challenges with RF compared to 4-layer designs, since the larger distance from signal layer to ground plane affects the RF negatively.
The Result 🔗Using the thinnest PCB stackup the board house offers (0.8mm), and adjusting the RF path accordingly (RF feedline 51&amp;ndash;58&amp;ndash;66 mil, keepaway 128 mil), the board has excellent RF performance while being a more cost efficient alternative to 4-layer designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Ethernet CC1310 Gateway - eth1310</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-eth1310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-eth1310/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: eth1310 🔗The Goal 🔗Design a sub-GHz to Ethernet gateway that is cost efficient. Minimize size while still being able to solder by hand.
The Challenge 🔗Ethernet and the CC1310 sub-GHz both present EMI challenges if not properly handled. RF and oscillator components should be as small as possible.
The Result 🔗4 layer stack-up, impedance controlled boards made by JLCPCB.
Ethernet chip is the Microchip ENC28J60. Hanrun connector with integrated magnetics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Wi-Fi CC1310 Gateway - wifi1310</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-wifi1310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-wifi1310/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: wifi1310 🔗The Goal 🔗I wanted to make a small, user-friendly gateway. It should connect a sub-GHz 6lowpan mesh network (think eg Thread, or Amazon Sidewalk) to the Internet, via Wi-Fi.
The Challenge 🔗Without the budget for custom RF work, nor space enough to be comfortable, make it work 😄.
Obviously RF must work and be compliant.
It must fit in a nice commercial off the shelf (COTS) pre-made enclosure, and provide mechanisms for USB power, status LEDs, button, programming and test points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Do It: Offline IoT</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-we-do-it-offline-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-we-do-it-offline-iot/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
When the wireless mesh is unavailable, store data locally.
A wireless mesh network reliably connects IoT (Internet of Things) devices, even in places where wireless is tricky.
But even with a wireless mesh network, the IoT devices may become disconnected. We then need to store their data offline – and have them automatically post their data when they come back online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: SLIP CC1310 Gateway - slip1310</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-slip1310/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-slip1310/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: serial1310 🔗Here&amp;rsquo;s the final result.
The Goal 🔗A small sub-GHz serial gateway that can fit in a Raspberry Pi enclosure, without external antenna. It must use a serial connection (UART) to connect to the Raspberry Pi, and in turn to the Internet over SLIP or PPP.
The Challenge 🔗Radio performance doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be fantastic, but it cannot be crappy or have compliance-destroying spurious emissions or such.
Cost-efficient, and simple to assemble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Antenna Design: Three Ways Your Antenna Deceives You</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/iot-antenna-design-three-ways-your-antenna-deceives-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/iot-antenna-design-three-ways-your-antenna-deceives-you/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
Every single Internet of Things (IoT) device needs an antenna.
The antenna is crucial: it may make or break the communication with your devices. A good antenna will give you a good wireless range. A bad antenna may cause your devices to not even be reachable in the field.
IoT devices are designed to be small, have a long wireless range, and have a long battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Good sub-GHz Range? A Reality Check</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/what-is-a-good-sub-ghz-range-a-reality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/what-is-a-good-sub-ghz-range-a-reality-check/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
What is the range of my sub-GHz IoT device?
Do the theoretical predictions of wireless range match the real world? We took a walk around the neighborhood to find out.
The answer to this question isn&amp;rsquo;t always what the theoretical models tell us. We wanted to see for ourselves how much the theory might differ from the real world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Reasons for 3D Printing IoT Prototypes</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/four-reasons-for-3d-printing-iot-prototypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/four-reasons-for-3d-printing-iot-prototypes/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
Make them good looking, robust, functional, and sellable.
At Thingsquare we use 3D printing for many of the IoT prototypes we build for customers.
Here are the top 4 reasons why we do it, and why you should do it too:
 Hide the electronics Make it more functional Make it easier to sell Make it robust  What is 3D Printing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Brewtag</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-brewtag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-brewtag/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Brewtag 🔗Soldered.
The Goal 🔗Design a small sensor board that runs off coin cell batteries and uses high-accuracy sensors.
The use case is to measure ambient pressure differences of an elevator moving from floor to floor, to keep track of what floors are visited and when.
The Challenge 🔗Small size, low cost, RF performance, EMI compliance, and protected against user errors such as battery upside down.
The pressure differences are quite small in the short travel distance between floors, so the pressure sensor must be quite accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Way to Measure the Power Consumption of Really Low-Power Hardware (for Software People)</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/a-new-way-to-measure-the-power-consumption-of-really-low-power-hardware-for-software-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/a-new-way-to-measure-the-power-consumption-of-really-low-power-hardware-for-software-people/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
We recently got a new tool at Thingsquare, which helps us ensure that we have extremely low power consumption of our software: the Otii Arc current and voltage measurement box, by Qoitech. This little box quickly lets us – a bunch of software persons – measure and understand the power consumption of the software that we run on our low-power hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Design Thingsquare-Compatible Hardware</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-to-design-thingsquare-compatible-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-to-design-thingsquare-compatible-hardware/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
Inside each connected product is a piece of hardware. This hardware typically has to be custom designed for each product, but the level of customization varies depending on the product.
Designing hardware for a Thingsquare-compatible product is straightforward because there are ready-made reference designs to use as a starting point.
Behind every successful product is a successful hardware design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Wireless Device that Lives Forever</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/designing-a-wireless-device-that-lives-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/designing-a-wireless-device-that-lives-forever/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
We have previously looked at how to make a wireless device live for years on one tiny coin cell battery. This time we up the game and make it live forever, using solar power and off-the-shelf hardware.
We build a prototype of our device and go through the technical details involved in designing for solar power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector graphics for your PCBs</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/vector-graphics-for-your-pcbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 22:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/vector-graphics-for-your-pcbs/</guid>
      <description>TLDR 🔗This tool converts SVG vector graphics to Cadsoft Eagle polygon. Get it here.
Why 🔗Technology can even in its most raw and bare form certainly be beautiful. The bottom of a motherboard, with long, parallell, impedance-matched traces from PCI-connectors is a good example. A large BGA is another, with traces extending in every direction.
I&#39;ve long wanted to make my PCBs more beautiful, taking the few &amp;quot;colors&amp;quot; into full use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clock with retro display</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/clock-with-retro-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 15:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/clock-with-retro-display/</guid>
      <description>HPDL-1414 clock 🔗After having ported Contiki to the Launchpad, I was eager on doing something with it. I built this simple clock with a vintage HPDL-1414 &amp;quot;smart four-character 16-segment alphanumeric&amp;quot; display and a msp430g2553.
The soldered clock from above and bottom. There is a lot of solder flux residue, and lots of small black pieces of fabric from my bag, which lessens the appeal of the white solder mask. Quite nice though.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
