<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>builds on Tiliaradix log</title>
    <link>https://tiliaradix.com/tags/builds/</link>
    <description>Recent content in builds on Tiliaradix log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiliaradix.com/tags/builds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build: Barnfind (in progress)</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-barnfind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-barnfind/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Barnfind (in progress) 🔗Sneak peek 🔗Meta 🔗It&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for various barn finds to pop into existance. The term more or less signifies something rare, forgotten in time and found way later. Often a rural farmer or excentric collector. While tanks aren&amp;rsquo;t that usual, more common is it to find old cars.
This diorama is a play on that theme.
Here, a farmer had a German WW2 tank in his barn, forgotten in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Subwoofer base</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-subwooferbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-subwooferbase/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Subwoofer base 🔗Sneak peek 🔗It stands.
Why 🔗We recently bought a soundbar system for our TV. The system includes a subwoofer. Not great, not terrible, but enough to potentially disturb neighbors. This calls for some kind of stand to separate the subwoofer-structure from the house-structure so the big badabooms doesn&amp;rsquo;t make for disturbance calls.
Also, the sides are dressed in a fabric mesh, and I want to raise it from the floor enough so that the vacuum cleaner won&amp;rsquo;t hit it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Clicker</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-clicker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-clicker/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Clicker 🔗Sneak peek 🔗Clicker diorama.
Meta 🔗The Clicker is a creature (?) in the world of The Last of Us, made by Naughty Dog.
Clicker.
The Clickers are originally humans, that have fallen to a fungus infection. The fungus, of the Cordyceps genus, affects, takes over, control over the body. It is famously documented on insects in the Planet Earth documentary, however the human infection is a fictious extrapolation as a plot device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Nixie (in progress)</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-nixie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-nixie/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Nixie (in progress) 🔗Sneak peek 🔗Before hitting the reflow oven.
Some Nixie tubes, IN-12A.
Some more Nixie tubes.
Meta 🔗Previously&amp;hellip; 🔗I saw this project, DekuNuken/exixe, and felt that hey, this is really cool and what I could use! But, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d like them differently.
For starters, I&amp;rsquo;d like them to run over I2C instead of SPI, to make it easier with strings of nixies. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to use firmware I&amp;rsquo;ve already developed (eg my contiki port for msp430) and chips I already had (msp430), aaaand I thought I could do a cleaner job with the layout of the transistors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Ohmu</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-ohmu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-ohmu/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Ohmu 🔗This is the buildlog for my Ohmu diorama.
Sneak peek 🔗Hello, Ohmu.
Meta 🔗The Ohmu is a creature from the 1984 anime Nausicaä of the Valley of the Wind.
It was directed by Hayao Miyazaki, who co-founded Studio Ghibli.
Brief synopsis courtesy of Wikipedia:
 Taking place in a future post-apocalyptic world, the film tells the story of Nausicaä (Shimamoto), the young princess of the Valley of the Wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: DigiDev</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-digidev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-digidev/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: DigiDev 🔗The Goal 🔗Design a board using inexpensive 2-layer design.
The Challenge 🔗2-layer designs present challenges with RF compared to 4-layer designs, since the larger distance from signal layer to ground plane affects the RF negatively.
The Result 🔗Using the thinnest PCB stackup the board house offers (0.8mm), and adjusting the RF path accordingly (RF feedline 51&amp;ndash;58&amp;ndash;66 mil, keepaway 128 mil), the board has excellent RF performance while being a more cost efficient alternative to 4-layer designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Ethernet CC1310 Gateway - eth1310</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-eth1310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-eth1310/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: eth1310 🔗The Goal 🔗Design a sub-GHz to Ethernet gateway that is cost efficient. Minimize size while still being able to solder by hand.
The Challenge 🔗Ethernet and the CC1310 sub-GHz both present EMI challenges if not properly handled. RF and oscillator components should be as small as possible.
The Result 🔗4 layer stack-up, impedance controlled boards made by JLCPCB.
Ethernet chip is the Microchip ENC28J60. Hanrun connector with integrated magnetics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Wi-Fi CC1310 Gateway - wifi1310</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-wifi1310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-wifi1310/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: wifi1310 🔗The Goal 🔗I wanted to make a small, user-friendly gateway. It should connect a sub-GHz 6lowpan mesh network (think eg Thread, or Amazon Sidewalk) to the Internet, via Wi-Fi.
The Challenge 🔗Without the budget for custom RF work, nor space enough to be comfortable, make it work 😄.
Obviously RF must work and be compliant.
It must fit in a nice commercial off the shelf (COTS) pre-made enclosure, and provide mechanisms for USB power, status LEDs, button, programming and test points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: SLIP CC1310 Gateway - slip1310</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-slip1310/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-slip1310/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: serial1310 🔗Here&amp;rsquo;s the final result.
The Goal 🔗A small sub-GHz serial gateway that can fit in a Raspberry Pi enclosure, without external antenna. It must use a serial connection (UART) to connect to the Raspberry Pi, and in turn to the Internet over SLIP or PPP.
The Challenge 🔗Radio performance doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be fantastic, but it cannot be crappy or have compliance-destroying spurious emissions or such.
Cost-efficient, and simple to assemble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Brewtag</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-brewtag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-brewtag/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Brewtag 🔗Soldered.
The Goal 🔗Design a small sensor board that runs off coin cell batteries and uses high-accuracy sensors.
The use case is to measure ambient pressure differences of an elevator moving from floor to floor, to keep track of what floors are visited and when.
The Challenge 🔗Small size, low cost, RF performance, EMI compliance, and protected against user errors such as battery upside down.
The pressure differences are quite small in the short travel distance between floors, so the pressure sensor must be quite accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflow Oven</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-reflow-oven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-reflow-oven/</guid>
      <description>Basic Low-cost Reflow Oven 🔗Sneak peek 🔗The reflow oven hard at work.
Meta 🔗&amp;ldquo;Professional&amp;rdquo; reflow ovens are pretty expensive.
Simple solution - use a small convection oven, add a precision temperature sensor and a controller, and let the controller heat the oven!
Why 🔗SMD components are smaller, and many many components doesn&amp;rsquo;t even come as through-hole parts (THP) nowadays. It&amp;rsquo;s also generally cheaper, and the resulting PCB can be made smaller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Big Red Button</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-big-red-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-big-red-button/</guid>
      <description>Buildlog: Big Red Button 🔗Sneak peek 🔗Meta 🔗The Big Red Button is a product from Sparkfun that evokes memories of arcade games.
With an appealing dome and satisfying loud click, you cannot not click the button. But it lacks an equally appealing enclosure.
Let&amp;rsquo;s build one out of concrete.
For this project, I used
 1 Texas Instruments Sensortag 1 Adafruit Big Red Button 1 RGB LED Prototyping cables Concrete Various things for concrete mold  Why 🔗Why not?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Wireless Device that Lives Forever</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/designing-a-wireless-device-that-lives-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/designing-a-wireless-device-that-lives-forever/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
We have previously looked at how to make a wireless device live for years on one tiny coin cell battery. This time we up the game and make it live forever, using solar power and off-the-shelf hardware.
We build a prototype of our device and go through the technical details involved in designing for solar power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector graphics for your PCBs</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/vector-graphics-for-your-pcbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 22:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/vector-graphics-for-your-pcbs/</guid>
      <description>TLDR 🔗This tool converts SVG vector graphics to Cadsoft Eagle polygon. Get it here.
Why 🔗Technology can even in its most raw and bare form certainly be beautiful. The bottom of a motherboard, with long, parallell, impedance-matched traces from PCI-connectors is a good example. A large BGA is another, with traces extending in every direction.
I&#39;ve long wanted to make my PCBs more beautiful, taking the few &amp;quot;colors&amp;quot; into full use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clock with retro display</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/clock-with-retro-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 15:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/clock-with-retro-display/</guid>
      <description>HPDL-1414 clock 🔗After having ported Contiki to the Launchpad, I was eager on doing something with it. I built this simple clock with a vintage HPDL-1414 &amp;quot;smart four-character 16-segment alphanumeric&amp;quot; display and a msp430g2553.
The soldered clock from above and bottom. There is a lot of solder flux residue, and lots of small black pieces of fabric from my bag, which lessens the appeal of the white solder mask. Quite nice though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: HTPC in NES enclosure</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-nes-htpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 11:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/builds/build-nes-htpc/</guid>
      <description>So Roger (a friend of mine) and I each bought ourselves a new HTPC. It is based on an Asus AT3IonT-I deluxe Mini-ITX motherboard in a NES chassis. The mobo has hardware accelerated decoding of HD material, built in WiFi, Bluetooth, comes with an IR remote, is fanless and uses a power brick instead of an ATX PSU.
Finished look. There&amp;rsquo;s an IR receiver eye in the black part.
This last point (and HW decoding of course) is key.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
