<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thingsquare on Tiliaradix Blog</title>
    <link>https://tiliaradix.com/tags/thingsquare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thingsquare on Tiliaradix Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiliaradix.com/tags/thingsquare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How We Do It: Making Things Happen At Specific Times of the Day</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-we-do-it-making-things-happen-at-specific-times-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-we-do-it-making-things-happen-at-specific-times-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
Connected products need scheduled actions. Scheduled actions require time synchronized deceives. Here is we make that happen.
In our daily lives, we are governed by time and schedules. We may wake up at 6:30 AM, take the bus at 7:34 AM, start work at 8:10 AM, pick up from school at 4:00 PM - based on synchronized and often fixed times of day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Do It: Offline IoT</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-we-do-it-offline-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-we-do-it-offline-iot/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
When the wireless mesh is unavailable, store data locally.
A wireless mesh network reliably connects IoT (Internet of Things) devices, even in places where wireless is tricky.
But even with a wireless mesh network, the IoT devices may become disconnected. We then need to store their data offline – and have them automatically post their data when they come back online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Antenna Design: Three Ways Your Antenna Deceives You</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/iot-antenna-design-three-ways-your-antenna-deceives-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/iot-antenna-design-three-ways-your-antenna-deceives-you/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
Every single Internet of Things (IoT) device needs an antenna.
The antenna is crucial: it may make or break the communication with your devices. A good antenna will give you a good wireless range. A bad antenna may cause your devices to not even be reachable in the field.
IoT devices are designed to be small, have a long wireless range, and have a long battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Good sub-GHz Range? A Reality Check</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/what-is-a-good-sub-ghz-range-a-reality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/what-is-a-good-sub-ghz-range-a-reality-check/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
What is the range of my sub-GHz IoT device?
Do the theoretical predictions of wireless range match the real world? We took a walk around the neighborhood to find out.
The answer to this question isn&amp;rsquo;t always what the theoretical models tell us. We wanted to see for ourselves how much the theory might differ from the real world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Reasons for 3D Printing IoT Prototypes</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/four-reasons-for-3d-printing-iot-prototypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/four-reasons-for-3d-printing-iot-prototypes/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
Make them good looking, robust, functional, and sellable.
At Thingsquare we use 3D printing for many of the IoT prototypes we build for customers.
Here are the top 4 reasons why we do it, and why you should do it too:
 Hide the electronics Make it more functional Make it easier to sell Make it robust  What is 3D Printing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Way to Measure the Power Consumption of Really Low-Power Hardware (for Software People)</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/a-new-way-to-measure-the-power-consumption-of-really-low-power-hardware-for-software-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/a-new-way-to-measure-the-power-consumption-of-really-low-power-hardware-for-software-people/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
We recently got a new tool at Thingsquare, which helps us ensure that we have extremely low power consumption of our software: the Otii Arc current and voltage measurement box, by Qoitech. This little box quickly lets us – a bunch of software persons – measure and understand the power consumption of the software that we run on our low-power hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Design Thingsquare-Compatible Hardware</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-to-design-thingsquare-compatible-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/how-to-design-thingsquare-compatible-hardware/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
Inside each connected product is a piece of hardware. This hardware typically has to be custom designed for each product, but the level of customization varies depending on the product.
Designing hardware for a Thingsquare-compatible product is straightforward because there are ready-made reference designs to use as a starting point.
Behind every successful product is a successful hardware design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Wireless Device that Lives Forever</title>
      <link>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/designing-a-wireless-device-that-lives-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiliaradix.com/posts/designing-a-wireless-device-that-lives-forever/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of a blog post made for thingsquare.com, slightly edited to fit this format.)
We have previously looked at how to make a wireless device live for years on one tiny coin cell battery. This time we up the game and make it live forever, using solar power and off-the-shelf hardware.
We build a prototype of our device and go through the technical details involved in designing for solar power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
